<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blue Planet]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Blue Planet</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:55:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:55:44 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Magic System]]></title><description><![CDATA[Magic is an inseperatible part of the world, just like physics laws (instead of using sciences people just explain everything with magic in this world, gravity is Earth's magic). Everyone just accepts it as it is, no one ever thinks that it's unrealistic. Some religions believe that a deity of their own granted magic to the world.As a natural force, magic can be used at first by a a limited number of magicians and then later widely popularized as magical artifacts. Some countries allow all of its citizens to use magic, while some limit magic to a certain group of people. The debate for this is complicated, and the power to control magic further contributes to inequalities in some countries.Born magic doesn't exist in this world, it all boils down to who learns to use magic well and who doesn't. People often need to go to magic schools to get license for using magic. Outlawed use of magic might get them jailed.While each country often have magic regulation laws of their own, international magic use is regulated by the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Aperium.md" href="worldbuilding/the-world/factions/aperium.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Aperium</a>. These are anointed knights (often called beekeepers) that go around to stop governments and international criminals from misusing magic.
Fundamentally, magic is finding the form for your intention. From this one law, magic has developed into many things within the past few centuries. Currently, there are a few major schools of magic:
Elemental: magic that shifts natural elements such as water, fire, soil,... Elemental magic is considered the oldest form of magic. The practice of using Elemental magic on a human body is heavily regulated. For example, only magicians with a healing license can cast certain elemental spells on their patients. Script: also called curse, magic that uses words (whether written or verbally) to deliver intents. By far the most popular form of magic for its application in manufacturing. Scripts can also be used to enhance or curse an existing object. The power of script is limited by the object's magic resistance. The higher this property, the less effect magic has on it. An ideal object needs to have as low resistance as possible.
The use of scripts on human body is banned by the Aperium. <br><a data-href="Formation" href="worldbuilding/rules/formation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Formation</a>: considered an advanced form of Elemental where the user could extract elements from an object and use these element to form something else. So far, not many people know about this practice. The most prominent user of Formation is Rostafr Nibelund. Alchemy is believed to be the early form of Formation. Alchemy was greatly disregarded as a real magic practice as its outcomes were inferior to other forms of magic. Generally, magic education is offered in limit in most countries. While most magic education institutions are considered higher education, some middle schools or high schools offer magic education to their best students. Families with magic traditions tend to teach their children magic from a young age, but this kind of education is unattainable to most families outside of the magic world.Magic education is divided into two streams:
Academic magic: students from this stream usually work in institutions to research new ways of applying magic. They sometimes get made fun of for being impractical and useless in urgent matters.
Applied magic: the more common stream, as students from this stream have a more diverse range of employment. They however don't have magic theory foundation as strong.
It has been a trend for nations to invest in magic education, however, this has also been heavily regulated by the Commission as they demand countries to limit the annual magic graduates to ensure all safety measures are followed properly.]]></description><link>worldbuilding/rules/magic-system.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Worldbuilding/Rules/Magic System.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:48:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Viên]]></title><description><![CDATA[Viên is a small city state located by the Salted Coast. Characterized by a rich history of immigration, Viên is a melting pot of cultures and is considered an important cultural and trading hub between the Eastern countries.Viên is a small city state located by the Salted Coast. Characterized by a rich history of immigration, Viên is a melting pot of cultures and is considered an important cultural and trading hub between the Eastern countries.-+
Location: East of the Continent
Demonym: Viênnese
Practiced religion(s): folk religions
Government: the Governor of Viên
Status: Active-+Apart from native Viennese, Viên has been home to Qiaao and Arvatakën minorities for a few centuries. These minorities integrate very well and still maintain their original cultures. Native Viennese generally accept them as their fellow Viennese and on the surface there's no discrimination. However, there has been debates on Vien's actual inclusivity towards these communities. Vien is also home to many international merchants who don't speak their language. Therefore, the average Viennese is bilingual and are somewhat used to foreigners. The merchants who open shops around the harbor area are called "boaties", locals love going here to get exports for a cheap price.Viennese architecture is built for resilience, as they have floods annually. Over the years, they have learnt to live with water with a lot of flood infrastructure and a substantial amount of elemental magician citizens.
Water puppet: an important aspect of the Viennese community. Water puppeteers often travel in coupes and are trained in singing as well as hydromancy.
Ceramics: Viennese ceramics usually come in blue and white.
Metalurgy: metal artifacts welded by Viennese blacksmiths are famous for their low magic resistance. Being the trading hubs for so many countries, Vien easily negates their lack of natural resources. Metal used for welding in Viên could come from anywhere.
Vien follows the standard calendar. A few holidays in Viên you might be interested:
Midsummer Festival: the Viennese celebrate this to pray for a year with mild floods.
Dragonsbreath Festival: a festival to honor Viennese metalurgy. Many blacksmiths come to Viên for this festival in August to showcase their crafts.
In general, Viennese people are extroverted and like to chat. They're essentially collectivists and can get very protective if an outsider is acting strange towards their people. They're also very quick to spot who isn't following their norms, and could be a bit standoff-ish to these people.
Viennese people often invite colleagues/friends/intermediate family over for dinner to strengthen bonds. It's common for important business meetings to happen over dinner.]]></description><link>worldbuilding/the-world/countries/viên.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Worldbuilding/The World/Countries/Viên.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:31:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wrisckaria]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:nation" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#nation">#nation</a>The Kingdom of Wrysckaria is a monarchy to the north of the Continent. The kingdom sits with its back facing the Nibelgas, the tallest mountain range in the Continent.
The capital city of Wrysckaria is Hjartgar, meaning Heart of the Garden. It is located at the heart of the hot spring system and is believed to be where Rautz buried the sacred Antle.-+
Capital: Hjartgar
Location: North of the Continent
Demonym: Wrysck
Practiced religion(s): Wrysck folk religion
Government: The Groninsken family
Status: Active-+Locating in the far North, Wrysckaria’s climate is defined by a mild summer and a harsh winter. Humidity is low all year round. The vast majority of Wrysckaria is populated around Hjartgar, the heart of the Nibelgas heated by a dense network of hotsprings underneath.Also called: the Northern Wall, the Grey Citadel
The Nibelgas is the largest mountain range in the Continent and has significantly defined Wrysckaria’s national identity. Ancient Wryscks believed that the range has been moulded by Rautz to protect their early settlement from the Northern Wind. The hot spring network of the mountain range plays a big part of Wrysckaria’s culture and economy, prompting many protection laws from the Groninsken family.Apart from the Wryscks, Otterfolks are also native to this land. Modern Wrisckaria and Wrisck people have done a lot of work on their racism towards Otterfolks, but in the past Otterfolks used to be isolated in their own neighborhoods. There is still a lot of activism going on.Wrysck buildings are short and sturdy to withstand the cold. Their rooftops are steep so snow falls off easily. The Wryscks are proud of their brickmaking, so little paint is used to show off the natural color of the bricks.Housing in Wrysckaria often have their own hotspring tubs. These are considered a sacred space of the family and they often invite honored guests inside to take bath with the entire family during special occasion.
Brickmaking is considered an art form of its own. Bricks are colored with the minerals found in Nibelgas' mines so they have a natural shininess. You can find colorful brick patterns everywhere in Wrysckaria.
Embroidery is taught to every child as it's considered a character building skill. A common pattern for beginner is the pinecone.
Leathermaking is also an important craft, as the Wrysck culture values sturdy material that they could use for a lifetime.
Wrysckaria follows the common calendar. They don't celebrate Midsummer as there is hardly a difference between early summer and mid-summer in Wrysckaria. However, their Spring festival has to be the biggest on the continent.
Spring Day: A week-long festival to celebrate the arrival of spring. It doesn't have a concrete timeframe, celebration starts as soon as snow has molten completely. People party at townsquares and there are usually parades.
Midnight Sun Festival: The winter solstice festival for the Wryscks. On this day, they usually get zero sunlight, and they usually light up an artificial sun to wish for a warm spring. A cozy time to be with family and closed ones.
]]></description><link>worldbuilding/the-world/countries/wrisckaria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Worldbuilding/The World/Countries/Wrisckaria.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:30:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Formation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Formation magic is a modern branch of magic considered to be an improvement of Elemental. Instead of manipulating natural elements, the user sees the world as component of modular components, or bolts, and either seperate or combine them to command magic. Formation magic was first coined in 995 by professor <a data-href="Arman Grachenaug" href="characters/the-academia/arman-grachenaug.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arman Grachenaug</a>.]]></description><link>worldbuilding/rules/formation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Worldbuilding/Rules/Formation.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:23:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aperium]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Aperium is the order that maintains international magic regulation laws in this world. It employs highly skilled people called Enforcers to make sure everyone follows the rule. Fetchers: officially Magical Artifact Retrievement division, these people are responsible for making sure high-grade artifacts are not astray.
]]></description><link>worldbuilding/the-world/factions/aperium.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Worldbuilding/The World/Factions/Aperium.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:50:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>